marketing-ideas.org 2012-11-17

# Privacy

The privacy of my visitors to Marketing-Ideas.org is VERY important to me.

At Marketing-Ideas.org, I understand the privacy of your personal information is important. Here's information on what types of personal information I collect when you use and visit my blog at Marketing-Ideas.org (and how I protect your information). I never sell your personal information to third parties – ever.

**Log Files**   
As with most other websites, I collect and analyze the data contained in traffic log files. The information in these log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Comcast), the browser you used to visit my site (such as Firefox or Safari), the amount of time you visited my blog (and which blogpages you visited throughout my site).

**Browser Cookies and Web Beacons**  
I do use cookies to store your information (such as your personal preferences when you visit my blog). This might include displaying a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of my other internet properties such as a message board.

I also use third-party advertisements on Marketing-Ideas.org to support my site. Some of these advertisers may use technology (such as browser cookies and web beacons) when they advertise on my blog… which also sends these advertisers (such as Google via their Google AdSense program)… information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit my blog – and in some cases, whether you have Adobe Flash installed. This is most often used for geotargeting purposes (showing Los Angeles real estate ads to someone in Los Angeles, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing online marketing courses ads to someone who frequents online marketing courses sites).

**DoubleClick DART cookies**  
I also may use DART cookies for serving ads via Google’s DoubleClick, which places a browser cookie on your computer when you are surfing the web and visit a website using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This browser cookie is used to display online ads targeted to you and your interests (a.k.a. "interest based targeting").

The ads displayed are going to be targeted based on your previous browsing history. (For example, if you've been viewing sites about visiting Orlando, you may see Orlando hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about organic recipes).

DART uses "non personally identifiable information". It does NOT track personal information about you per se (such as your name, email address, postal address, phone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers). You can easily opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this form of advertising by visiting:

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off the browser or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this might affect how you're able to interact with our site (as well as other websites). This might include the inability to login to my services or features (such as logging into message board or accounts).

Deleting browser cookies doesn't mean you're permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow browser cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new browser cookie is going to be added.
